hi everyone welcome to learn English with podcast conversations I'm your host
Emma and today I'm joined by Anna an English teacher hi Anna how are
you hi Emma I'm doing great thank you how about you I'm good thanks I'm very
excited to talk to you about our topic today which is early Rising do you know
what early Rising means Anna yes I do early Rising means getting up early in
the morning usually Before Sunrise or before most people wake up that's right
and why do you think some people choose to be early risers
Anna well there are many possible reasons Emma some people may have to
wake up early for work or school or to take care of their family or pets some
people may want to wake up early to have more time for themselves to do some
exercise meditation reading or other Hobbies some people may believe that
waking up early can make them more productive creative or
happy I see and what about you Anna are you an early riser
yourself actually I am Emma I usually wake up around 5 a m every day wow
that's impressive how do you manage to do that Anna well Emma it's not easy I
admit it took me some time and effort to develop this habit of early Rising but I
think it's worth it because I enjoy the benefits of waking up early what are
some of the benefits that you enjoy Anna first of all I enjoy the peace and quiet
of the early morning there is less noise traffic and distraction I can focus on
myself and my goals I can plan my day ahead and set my
priorities I can also do some activities that I love such as yoga yoga journaling
or listening to podcasts that sounds wonderful Anna I
can see how waking up early can help you start your day on a positive note yes
exactly another benefit that I enjoy is that I feel more energetic and alert
throughout the day I don't feel sleepy or sluggish in the afternoon I can
accomplish more tasks and be more efficient I can also handle stress and
challenges better because I have a clear mind in a good mood I agree Anna I think
waking up early can boost your physical and mental health it can also improve
your quality of sleep because you are more likely to go to bed earlier and
have a regular sleep schedule that's true Emma a good night sleep is
essential for your well-being it can help you recover from fatigue enhance
your memory and strengthen your immune system wow Anna you have convinced me
that waking up early has many advantages but I have a question for you how do you
actually wake up early do you have any tips or tricks that you can share with
us of course Emma I'm happy to share some tips and tricks that work for me
but I want to remind you that everyone is different and what works for me may
not work for you you have to experiment and find out what suits you best that's
a good point Anna thank you for being honest and
realistic you're welcome Emma so the first tip that I have is to have a
strong motivation for waking up early you have to know why you want to do it
and what benefits you expect to gain from it you have to have a clear goal
and a vision that inspires you and drives you I see so for example if I
want to wake up early to learn English I have to remind myself of how much I love
English and how much I want to improve my skills and
confidence exactly Emma you have to keep your passion and
purpose in mind and use them as your fuel you can also write down your goal
and your reasons and put them somewhere you can see them every morning such as
your bedside table your wall or your phone that's a great idea Anna I think
that can help me stay focused and motivated the second tip that I have is
to prepare everything you need the night before you have to make it easy for
yourself to wake up early and eliminate any obstacles or excuses that may stop
you you have to plan your morning routine and set up your environment
accordingly what do you mean by that Anna I mean that you have to prepare
everything you need for your morning activities such as your clothes your
breakfast your books your laptop Etc you have to make sure that everything is
ready and accessible so that you don't waste time or energy looking for them or
making them in the morning I understand so for example if I want to wake up
early to do some yoga I have to lay out my yoga man my yoga clothes and my water
bottle the night before exactly Emma you have to make it
as convenient and simple as possible for yourself to follow your morning routine
you can also set up some cues or reminders that can help you get started
such as an alarm a note a picture or a playlist that makes sense Anna I think
that can help me overcome my inertia and LA
the third tip that I have is to adjust your bedtime gradually you have to make
sure that you get enough sleep otherwise you will feel tired and miserable in the
morning you have to go to bed earlier and avoid any distractions or stimulants
that can keep you awake such as your phone your TV your coffee or your
alcohol I agree Anna sleep is very important for your health and
performance but how can I go to bed earlier if I'm used to staying up plate
well Emma you can't change your habits overnight you have to do it step by step
and be consistent you can start by going to bed 15 minutes earlier than usual and
then gradually increase the time until you reach your desired
bedtime you can also use some tools or techniques that can help you fall asleep
faster such as meditation breathing exercises aroma therapy or relaxing
music I see so for example if I want to wake up at 6 a m and I need 8 hours of
sleep I have to go to bed by 10 p m but if I usually go to bed at midnight I
have to start by going to bed at 11:45 p n and then 1130 pm. and so on until I
reach 10 p.m. that's right Emma you have to be patient and persistent and not
give up you have to reward yourself for your progress and celebr celebrate your
achievements the fourth tip that I have is to have a buddy or a partner who can
support you and hold you accountable you have to find someone who shares your
goal of waking up early and who can motivate you and challenge you you have
to communicate with them regularly and check on each other's progress and
difficulties I like that idea Anna I think having a buddy or a partner can
make the journey more fun and rewarding but how can I find someone who is is
willing to wake up early with me well Emma you can start by asking your
friends family or colleagues if they're interested in joining you you can also
join some online communities or groups that are dedicated to early Rising such
as forums blogs podcasts or social media platforms you can also use some apps or
websites that can help you find and connect with other early risers such as
wake up early bird or rise wow Anna you have done your research I didn't know
there were so many resources and tools that can help me find a buddy or a
partner for waking up early yes Emma there are and I encourage you to explore
them and see what works for you you may be surprised by how many people are
willing to support you and join you in your quest thank you Anna I appreciate
your advice and your encouragement you're very welcome Emma the fifth and
Final tip that I have is to be flexible and adaptable you have to understand
that waking up early is not a one-size fits all solution and that it may not
work for everyone or every situation you have to listen to your body and your
needs and adjust your schedule accordingly what do you mean by that
Anna I mean that you have to be realistic and flexible about your goal
of waking up early you have to accept that there may be some days when you
can't or don't want to wake up early and that's okay you don't have to feel
guilty or disappointed you can just try again the
next day I see so for example if I have a late night out with my friends or if
I'm feeling sick or if it's a weekend I can allow myself to sleep in a little
bit exactly Emma you have to be kind and gentle with yourself and not force
yourself to do something that doesn't suit you or your
situation you have to find a balance between your goal and your lifestyle and
adapt to the changes and challenges that may arise that makes sense Anna I think
being flexible and adaptable can help me avoid frustration and burnout yes Emma
it can and it can also help you enjoy the process and the journey of waking up
early and not just the outcome or the result thank you Anna you have given me
a lot of valuable tips and tricks that can help me become an early riser sir
I'm very grateful for your help and your expertise you're very welcome Emma it's
my pleasure to help you and to share my experience with you I hope you find
these tips and tricks useful and effective and I hope you achieve your
goal of waking up early thank you Anna I appreciate your support and your
encouragement you're welcome Emma and thank you for listening to this episode
of learn English with podcast conversation
I hope you enjoyed it and learned something new if you have any questions
or comments please feel free to contact us or leave a review we would love to
hear from you and don't forget to subscribe to our podcast so you don't
miss any of our future episodes until next time bye for
now